Ahmed Mohamed Gharib

Digital Marketing Manager

Contact information

Phone1: 002-01001161903 Phone2: 002-01127999940

Address: 12 Palm City, Qatamya, Cairo, Egypt.

Email1: Amgharib1983@gmail.com

Web

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedmgharib/Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/amgharib/

About

When I realized strength of marketing in various practical fields, I shifted my career path from financial markets to digital marketing. With the scientific study of marketing, I was able to help many start-ups in creating their brand and growth, as well as achieving the required sales through my marketing plans in the last 5 years. Also, the operating companies I able to raise their sales and revenue level by 20-30% during timeline not exceeding 3 months using data analytics and market analysis to brand development and product development.

One of the strongest points in my personality is my ability to work strongly, whether independently or as part of a team, and Building communications in teamwork and self-motivation to achieve goals and key performance indicators while meeting the required deadlines while maintaining the highest standards. Exploiting all marketing strategies, web analytics, market research, marketing materials, data management and brainstorming with a team to develop marketing strategies to aim goals and return on investment.

Many skills I gained since 2002 especially from financial markets and the forex market such as budget forecasting, cash handling, cost control, cost reduction, strategic and financial planning, relationship building and management, and long-term planning. Which highly qualifies me to do business development, revenue generation, financial analysis, reporting, management and consultancy to make companies management more effective.

Experience

STEAMAD Media Agency - Cairo, Egypt

Digital Marketing Manager

August 2020 - NOW

- Innovating and brainstorming with team to setup marketing strategy and execution plan, by 20% above KPIs in all marketing assets.
- Coordinating with the management to share funnel conversion improvement ideas, feedback and present results.
- Handling various social channels like facebook, twitter, instagram and linkedIn in paid and non-paid campaigns.
- Acquire revenue gain by average 20% in first 3 months only by Content Development in Social media activities speaking to target customers atracting them to deal with us.
- Analyze consumer behaviorfor clients, SEM strategy development, SEO devolopment, Event networking, Calculating ROI, Content Management, Web Development and Strategic planning.
- Identifying and testing new benchmarks and KPIs to measure the progress for clients by marketing.
- Audit and approve marketing material, from website banners to hard copy brochures and case studies.
- Campaign management by Measure and report on the performance of campaigns and compare with targeted KPIs and ROI.
- Update Social Media Strategies, Social Media Marketing, Social Media Campaign, Email Marketing by New Business Development tools which upgrade the progress for whole company by average 50%.
- Follow new trends and select the best one fit our client, follow event calendar and schedule for making Strategic planning for monthly, quarterly, semi-annually and annually.
- Upgrading team by hiring pioneers to Increase ability of performance by at least 70%. With keeping all my responsibilities in old position.

OKSHO Media Agency - Cairo, Egypt

Digital media Manager

October 2017 – July 2020

- Setting-up, Designing and monitoring digital marketing departments, marketing database, emails, and display advertising campaigns.
- Define, implement and monitor campaign budgets, SWOT Analysis, Marketing Mix (7Ps and 4Cs) and digital marketing KPIs.
- Plan and manage our social media platforms, Prepare accurate reports on our marketing campaign's overall performance.
- Coordinate with advertising and media experts to improve marketing results, Identify the latest trends and technologies affecting our industry.
- Evaluate important metrics that affect our website traffic, service quotas, and target audience.
- Work with team to brainstorm new and innovative growth strategies, Oversee and manage all contests, giveaways, and other digital projects.
- Establishing an improved work team by recruiting new employees with practical experience.

Social media Manager

- Develop, implement and manage social media strategy, important social media KPIs, Manage and oversee social media content and Measure the success of every social media campaign.
- Use social media marketing tools such as Buffer, attend educational conferences and Stay up to date with latest social media best practices and technologies.
- Work with copywriters and designers to ensure content is informative and appealing, Collaborate with Marketing, Sales and Product Development teams and Monitor SEO and user engagement and suggest content optimization.
- Communicate with industry professionals and influencers via social media to create a strong network.
- Provide constructive feedback, Adhere to rules and regulations and Present to Senior Management. Social media specialist
- Execute and manage social media strategy and Define most important social media KPIs.
- Sort and write social media content with practice to make social media campaign.
- Stay up to date with the latest social media best trends.

RAK Co-operative Society - Ras Al Khaimah, UAE

Financial and general Accountant

March 2016 - Feb 2017

The Biggest Retail market in food in RAK which I was responsible for:

- Place the monthly profit and loss, balance sheet reports and state quarterly and annual statements.
- Checking and arranging invoices and other bills for suppliers and Tax reporting and inventory processing.
- Result KPI reports and Advising on estimates for projects funding.
- Equip weekly cash flow statements, and controlling expenditure and cash flow and Assisting with the preparation of year-end accounts and statutory accounts.
- Examining financial records to check for accuracy and Conducting internal audits such as wage reviews.
- Calculating petty cash vouchers & Salary voucher in head office and deal with national and international banks in RAK.

FXFUTURE Co and Academy – Dubai, UAE

Chief Financial Officer

July 2015 – Feb 2016

With the Management consultancy in FXBORSSA. Worked with FXFUTURE as an CFO and was responsible for:

- Review of analysis of all teams (about 25 daily analysis) and Make my own analysis of basic currencies and metals.
- Set daily recommendations for clients in basic and cross currencies. to achieve all requirements of clients and their ROI.
- Create risk tolerance for each client to determine the risk percentage to manage portfolios with Apply profit and risk factors that signed by clients.
- Record monthly profit in average 4.5-5.5% in clients according to their risk tolerances with respecting and implement of our policy and NFA, FCA standards.
- Maintain deal record and P&L on a daily basis and discuss directly with customers, Following up the assigned budget and risk.
- Instructor in technical analysis in forex and money markets, Organize events (sales and teaching events) and forex courses.

FXBORSSA Co and Academy - Cairo, Egypt

Management and portfolios consultant

Jan 2010 - Sep 2017

- Set daily recommendations for clients in basic and cross currencies in weekly video. to satisfy all requirements of clients and their ROI.
- Generate about 48-60% yearly profit in portfolios by conservative Risk management and audit all transactions to be sure it is applied with agency policy and NFA, FCA standards.
- Supervise all events represent FXBORSSA in national and international events in whole middle east.

Executive Director of FXBORSSA.

- Expanding f FXBORSSA to be an agent for large companies of forex like FXDD, CITY INDEX and FXCM which Increased duties and challenges to solve.
- Review analysis of all teams (about 15 daily analysis), Make my own analysis of basic currencies and metals in weekly video.
- Set daily recommendations for clients in basic and cross currencies in weekly video. to fulfil all requirements of clients and their ROI.
- Obtain average 2-3% monthly profit gain in portfolios by calculating risk management following agency policy and NFA, FCA standards.
- Put swing recommendations to clients to Maximize Profit and Minimize risk within acceptability through Market Making, Positioning and Trading within approved limits and policies and procedures.
- Organize events (sales and teaching events), Represent FXBORSSA and share in international stocks and forex events in whole middle east (DUBAI, RIYADH, DOHA, AMMAN, CAIRO and KUWAIT).

Vice-president of ICTA. as a part of FXBORSSA Academy

- Transferring from FXHORUS to FXBORSSA with more tools in forex market like ICTA (International Chamber of Technical Analysts) which is a chamber teach all kinds of financial markets and forex like technical analysis, fundamental analysis, financial analysis and accounting courses.
- I became a Vice-president of ICTA with all my duties of Supervision and instructor with all past duties.

Primary Supervisor of forum and instructor.

• FXHORUS activate an academy for teaching technical analysis and money market's structure which I become also an instructor in technical analysis in forex and money markets with all my responsibilities as a Supervisor of forum to teach basics of technical analysis and fundamental analysis.

Supervisor of forum.

- Started with FXHORUS as a Supervisor of forum in forex markets and did Basic analysis for Forex charts (basic and cross currencies).
- Review of analysis of my team (5 technical analysts).
- to Set daily recommendations for clients in basic and cross currencies.
- put basic analysis for Egypt stock market.
- managing the requirements of clients under our IB (Introducing Broker) and Meet with them when requested.

RICH FINANCIAL CONSULTED MIDDLE EAST - Doha, Qatar

Technical Analyst

March 2008 – Dec 2009

- Understand all basics of Technical analysis and candles, put analysis for Forex charts (basic currencies).
- Put basic analysis for Qatar stock market, Set daily recommendations for clients in basic currencies.

Federal Travel Agency Ltd - Doha, Qatar

Financial Accountant

Nov 2006 - Feb 2008

- Enrolling day to day accounting activities, Preparation of Journal voucher, Handling Daily financial transaction and record Debit Note & Credit Note.
- Follow up Receivables, Set Invoice for Ticket & Hotel Reservation, Refund notice, and Reconciliation with vendor's account.
- Checking and arranging invoices and other bills, Preparation of various accounts related reports, Bank Reconciliation statement and deal with national and international banks in DOHA.
- Preparation of payment vouchers and arrange payment, Profit & Loss Account, Balance Sheet, petty cash vouchers & Salary voucher.

MASRAWY COMPUTER CO. – Cairo, Egypt

Partner in small business

July 2005 - Oct 2006

- As a partner in this co I was responsible for all accounting section deals with vendors and clients.
- Establish administration duties for handling our staff.

NSGB (NATIONAL SOCIETE GENERAL BANK) – Cairo, Egypt

Assistant Teller Trainee Teller Jan 2005 – March 2005 July 2004 – Oct 2004

- As a teller assistant Deal with clients in deposit, withdraw, cash transfer and other actions on their accounts.
- Discover rules of banks, Bank interest, credit and debit cards, loans and the system of central bank.

SMART COMPUTER – Tanta, Egypt

Accountant

Oct 2002 - March 2004

As an accountant I Handling Daily transaction, preserve day to day vouchers of sales and purchases, Output Debit Note & Credit Note and all reports.

Certifications

DM ARTS – Cairo, Egypt

March 2017

Digital Marketing course allow me to discover Basics and meaning of marketing, Digital marketing, social media, digital marketing Plan and strategy, meaning of Branding and awareness, what The KPIs and how you can obtain.

Building social media pages in all platform, generate targeting audience and make ads, basics of content creation, analysis for pages and competitors, and SWOT analysis.

CFA INSTITUTE - Charlottesville VA, USA

June 2010

Self-study with a practice in AUC (American university in Cairo) then pass CFA level one exam with ID: 6427334

Universal Broker - Boston, USA

Sep 2008

Technical analysis of foreign exchange market

Tech me to analyse all kinds of financial and stocks charts with technical ways and dealing with all kinds of candle, bars and liner charts.

Education

TANTA UNIVERSITY FACULTY OF COMMERCE (ENGLISH SECTION) - Tanta, Egypt

July 2005

Bachelor in Accounting with Degree of Grad: Pass

Languages

Arabic: Native language

English: Fluent

Software

Microsoft windows

Mac OS

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Power point

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe After Effects

Pioneer Accounting

Meta Trader 4&5

Mubashir